pioneer.com 2012-12-15

# DuPont Pioneer | Privacy

**Privacy Statement**

STATEMENT REGARDING USE OF YOUR BUSINESS AND PERSONAL INFORMATION

**TABLE OF CONTENTS**

  *  General
  *  How Does Pioneer Collect Business Information?
  *  How Does Pioneer Use the Business Information it Has Collected From You?
  *  To Whom Will Pioneer Provide Your Business Information?
  *  What is Personal Information?
  *  What Personal Information Does Pioneer Collect and How Does Pioneer Use the Personal Information?
  *  With Whom Does Pioneer Share Personal Information?
  *  Information Collected Through the Use of Technology
  *  My Farms and Fields Account Information
  *  Information Voluntarily Sent to Pioneer or This Pioneer Site by You
  *  What Type of Security Does Pioneer Provide?
  *  Links and Disclaimers of Linked Sites
  *  Contacts Regarding Questions or Concerns About This Privacy Statement

**GENERAL**

We at Pioneer Hi-Bred International, Inc., ("Pioneer") are committed to maintaining the privacy and security of the personal information or data of all visitors to this web site. As a part of that commitment, Pioneer is in the process of implementing its Information Privacy Policy for the United States and Canada. This Statement is intended to let our visitors and customers know what business information and personal information about them we collect at this Pioneer web site, www.Pioneer.com/growingpoint (the "Pioneer Site") why we collect it, and the purposes for which it is used and disclosed. At this Pioneer Site, Pioneer collects information in a number of ways:

**BUSINESS INFORMATION**

**How does Pioneer collect business information?**   
At this Pioneer Site, Pioneer primarily collects information about our customers' business/farm operations such as address, phone numbers, employees, acres, crop protection used, etc. If the information requested relates to your farming operation(s), it is generally considered business information, not personal information. Additionally, we collect similar business information about the businesses that support our customers, such as crop consultants, professional farm managers, agricultural retailer's and distributors, food and feed processors, grain merchandisers, elevators, and coops to name a few.

Pioneer takes the information we collect at this Pioneer Site and syncs it up with our databases to provide you with a customized look and service that includes providing you with information specific to your operation or business. For example, as a customer you will receive weather and agronomic information specific to your region as well as identifying the Pioneer sales contact in your area. Additionally, we can provide you with information about products specific to your area and needs.

**How does Pioneer use the business information it has collected from you?**   
Pioneer uses the information we collect on this Pioneer Site to provide you and the businesses that support you with services related to the Pioneer Site. Pioneer may use any of the business information gathered at this Pioneer Site for any legal purposes, including but not limited to, for direct marketing; or we may also analyze it for historical, statistical or scientific purposes, or we may store it for your convenience should you return to this site in the future.

**To whom will Pioneer provide your business information?**   
We may provide your business information to Pioneer affiliates or other third parties for a number of purposes, including but not limited to circumstances where we believe sharing that information may result in your having access or connection to services and products that enhance your operation, or instances that include expanding the options you have for selling your products. Additionally, we may share business information to investigate security breaches, or to co-operate with authorities pursuant to a legal matter.

**PERSONAL INFORMATION**

**What is Personal Information?**   
Personal information is any information about an identifiable person, other than the name, title or business address or telephone number, or other business contact information of an employee of an organization ("Personal Information"). Personal Information does not include business information. Except as detailed in Section IV on collection through use of Technology, when Pioneer collects Personal Information, it will ask for your consent at the point of collection and reference you to this Statement detailing the purposes for which Pioneer collects, uses and discloses such Personal Information. An example of a location where we might collect Personal Information and you would receive a notice asking for your consent would be the Country Store.

**What Personal Information does Pioneer collect and how does Pioneer use the Personal Information?**   
Personal Information is collected and used in accordance with this Statement and the Information Privacy Policy. For example, at this Pioneer Site, we collect information that may be personal at the pages titled Registration Form, Set Preferences, Contact Us, Country Store, Seed Information Requests, and Product Selection. Pioneer syncs up the information provided by you with our database and our sales representatives to determine if you are one of our business customers or business prospects or a business that supports our customers. If there is a match, your information is used in accordance with our practices detailed above under Part II above, "Business Information."

If there is not a match, the information collected will be treated as Personal Information, and in each case will be used only for the purposes of (a) providing you with the specific service associated with this Pioneer Site for which you have provided your Personal Information (which service may include contacting you via this Pioneer Site about programs, questionnaires, games, and contests; or providing you with feedback, assistance and guidance related to agriculture in general and/or specifically related to questions you have or may submit, except to the extent you have indicated that you do not wish to be contacted by email related to the above by going to "Set Preferences" and checking the box indicating you do not wish to be so contacted); and (b) storing it for your convenience should you return to this site in the future, to be used so that you do not need to re-register on the Pioneer Site or re-set your "Set Preferences". Should you not wish Pioneer to store and use your Personal Information as set out in (b) above, send us an email requesting same to [Privacy Coordinator](mailto:Support@pioneer.com?Subject=Please%20do%20not%20store%20my%20personal%20information).

Personal information, including payment information collected at this Pioneer Site at the Country Store, such as your credit card number and expiration date ("Payment Information"), are used and disclosed to third parties only for the purpose of providing you with the service associated with this Pioneer Site for which you have provided your Personal Information, which service may include making, completing and collecting on a transaction in the normal course of business.

**With whom does Pioneer share Personal Information?**   
Personal Information may be shared with Pioneer affiliates and other third party service providers, such as data processing contractors that manage systems and/or data on our behalf, only for the purpose of providing you with the service associated with this Pioneer Site for which you have provided your Personal Information. In addition, Pioneer may use and share Personal Information to investigate security breaches, or to co-operate with authorities pursuant to a legal matter, or where authorized by law.

Whenever any Personal Information is transferred to a third party, that party will be contractually bound to abide by our Information Privacy Policy.

**Information collected through the use of technology**   
First, we may actively collect information that is automatically sent to us by your web browser. This information typically includes your domain name (which typically means your internet service provider, browser, type and version, and your operating system). The amount of information sent depends on the settings you have on your web browser; please refer to your browser if you want to learn what information it sends.

We use the information we automatically receive from your web browser to see which pages you visit within our Pioneer Site, which site you visited before coming to ours, and where you go after you leave. We at Pioneer can then develop statistics that are very helpful in understanding how this Pioneer Site is used by our visitors. This statistical data is used by Pioneer in its continuing effort to present the content that customers are seeking in a format they find most helpful.

Second, we may actively obtain information about you by installing our own marker on your computer. This marker is commonly called a "cookie" and it enables us to know you by a computer-generated, unique identifier. By providing you a unique identifier, we are able to store your previous choices and preferences on your machine. In situations where these choices or preferences need to be used again; they can be supplied to us by your machine automatically, saving you time and effort. For example, if you purchase a product once, and you want to purchase it again, your previous selections for size, quantity or other features will have been retained, and can be re-entered more quickly. Your computer may be specifically configured to reject cookies; please refer to your browser for more information.

**My Farms and Fields Account Information**   
My Farms & Fields information is provided as a service to you to record and track field operations and applications. It is considered business information. Even so, you may elect to share only your basic Farms & Fields information. Should you choose only share the basic information, restricted access to the rest of your Farms & Fields information will be given to a limited set of Pioneer employees and their assignees to the extent such access is necessary to administer the site. In addition, all of your data may be used in aggregate for reporting purposes.

**Information voluntarily sent to Pioneer or this Pioneer Site by You.**   
We also collect information at this Pioneer Site when you contact us or respond to the surveys, questionnaires or applications we make available on the Pioneer Site. If you contact us or respond to such surveys, questionnaires or applications, or e-mail us, you are voluntarily releasing information to us. We use that information and share it as necessary only for the purpose of providing you the information, services and/or products specifically requested by you in each case. If you email us, or answer questions we have placed on the page, you are also voluntarily releasing that information to us and thereby consent to our use of that information as to provide you the information, services and/or products specifically requested by you in each case. (You may decide not to answer any questions; if you do, you may still continue your visit, but we may not be able to provide you the information, services and/or products.)

**SECURITY**

**What type of security does Pioneer provide?**   
The importance of security for all business and Personal Information collected through the Pioneer Site is of utmost concern to us. We have taken technical, contractual, administrative and physical security steps to protect the information collected from you on this site which are appropriate to the sensitivity of the information collected and the notices provided.

However, there are some things that users can do to help protect the security of this Personal Information as well. For instance, users should never give out their password. Also, every user should click on the "log out" button on GrowingPoint and close their browser window when they finish surfing the Web so that other people using the same computer won't have access to the information.

**Links and Disclaimers of Linked Sites**   
For your convenience, the Pioneer Site may contain certain hyperlinks to other Pioneer pages as well as to sites outside Pioneer. Please note that once you have clicked on a link, you may leave the Pioneer Site to a site that is not under our control and to which our Information Privacy Policy does not apply. You must read the privacy policy, if any, of each linked site to see how your Personal Information will be collected, used and disclosed on their site.

**Contacts regarding questions or concerns about this Privacy Statement**   
If you have any questions about this statement, our Pioneer Information Privacy Policy, or anything else related to Pioneer's collection, use and disclosure of Personal Information, please write to us at Pioneer Hi-Bred International, Inc., Attention Pioneer website - Privacy Coordinator, 7100 N.W. 62nd Ave, Johnston, Iowa or send us an email to [support@pioneer.com](mailto:support@pioneer.com). 

Effective date: November 10, 2000. Last Updated: September 19, 2003.
